A Guide to the Undergraduate English Honors Theses, 1979-1994
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Undergraduate English Honors Theses 1979-1994
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-22/1/3.031
This collection consists of 262 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred by the Department of English.
Scope and Content Information
This collection are honors theses written by students in the Department of English.
Contents List
- "The Petrarchan Tradition in Sixteenth Century English Poetry" by Marcia Lynn Arthur 1979 (Box 1)
- "The Legend of King Arthur: The Stuff that Dreams Are Made Of" by Margaret Lella Birdsong 1979 (Box 1)
- "Illustration and Design as Literary Interpretation: Aspects of the Work of Warren Chappell" by Peter Brehm 1979 (Box 1)
- "Between the Lines: A Collection of Stories" by David Doyle 1979 (Box 1)
- "Aspects of Critical Theory: Four Analytic Essays Toward A Theory of Literature" by Joel Briar Hamilton 1979 (Box 1)
- "Student's Guide to Thomas Pynchon" by Michael Heasley 1979 (Box 1)
- "Solitude and Obsessions: The Fiction of Gabriel Garcia Marquez" by Betsy Kulamer 1979 (Box 1)
- "A Study of Ghosts in the Literature of Jack Kerouac" by Brian T. MacDowell 1979 (Box 1)
- "Wallace Steven's Faith in the Poet: The Dissonant Marriage of Imagination and Reality" by Michael H. Martz 1979 (Box 2)
- "A Creative Writing Honors Thesis in Two Parts: Part I-Body Currents and Part II- Themes and Influences In My Work" by Joan M. Mullany 1979 (Box 2)
- "Tennessee Williams: A World Lit by Lightning" by Virginia Munsch 1979 (Box 2)
- "Shakespeare and Sidney: The power of the Imagination" by Martha Brentwood Murray 1979 (Box 2)
- "Gertrude Stein's Spatial Writing and William James' Psychology: The Reading Process and Its Limits" by Parke P. Muth 1979 (Box 2)
- " The Unvanquished: Bayard Sartoris' Search for Identity" by Zachary Mark Solomon 1979 (Box 2)
- "Softly Beyond the Twilit Door: The Form and Function of three Social Structure in Yoknapatawpha County" by Allen R. Swope 1979 (Box 2)
- "The Art of Achieving an Identity" by Elaine D. Washington 1979 (Box 2)
- " Paradise Regained and the Temptation Motif in Milton" by John Amos 1980 (Box 2)
- "Jacobean Tragicomedy: A Study of Guarini, Beaumont and Fletcher, and Shakespeare" by Dale Critz Jr. 1980 (Box 2)
- "Chaos and Continuity: Vision as George Eliot's Response to Her Times" by Victoria Dettmar 1980 (Box 2)
- "And All This Evil Turn to Good: Divine Providence in the Miltonic Christian Cosmos" by Peder M. Field 1980 (Box 3)
- "George Eliot's Philosophical Focus on Redemption and Vision" by Pamela Gibbs 1980 (Box 3)
- "Tradition and Transition: George Gascoigne as Comic Playwright" by Ann C. Houston 1980 (Box 3)
- "A Critical Study of the Works of Punyakante Wijenaike" by Catheeja Ismail 1980 (Box 3)
- "The Return of the Beloved Dead in Edgar Allen Poe" by Jack Jennings 1980 (Box 3)
- "Dionysus Disguised: Tragedy and Self-Consciousness in the Modern Novel" by Rodney Jones 1980 (Box 3)
- "The Lost Generation: Ravaged by the Great War" by Lisa A. Kaufman 1980 (Box 3)
- "A Spirit Capable" by Lisa Krueger 1980 (Box 3)
- "Contemporary Jewish Consciousness in Saul Bellow, Bernard Malamud, and Philip Roth" by Marc J. Lewyn 1980 (Box 3)
- "Toward the Emerging Mind: Images of Imagination in Coleridge, Yeats, and Stevens" by Mary T. Marshall 1980 (Box 3)
- "Humor and the Drama of Life: Character Depiction and Moral Purpose in the Works of Hogarth and Fielding" by Robert Micou 1980 (Box 4)
- "Thomas Wolfe: The Promise of Youth" by Laura L. Mitchell 1980 (Box 4)
- "From Templeton to Europe and Back: The American Gentleman in Cooper's Novel's, 1823-1838" by Ronald L. Morris 1980 (Box 4)
- "Revisions of Time: The Relationship of History and Romance in Cymbeline and The Tempest" by Susanna Nicholson 1980 (Box 4)
- "In a Southern Tradition: The Works of Walker Percy, Ernest Gaines and Shelby Foote" by Gary L. Sligh 1980 (Box 4)
- "The Characterization and Development of the Negro in the Works of William Faulkner" by Michael F. Taylor 1980 (Box 4)
- "Women in Late Nineteenth Century: Fact and Fiction" by Elizabeth Yntema 1980 (Box 4)
- "Native Sources and the Heroic Concept in the Literature of the Irish Renaissance by Lawrence J. Bracken, II 1981 (Box 4)
- "Until the Final Trumpet Sounds: The Apocalyptic Symbolism in Petersburg and The Silver Dove" by Art Coleman 1981 (Box 4)
- "The Rise of the Individual and the Quest for Perfection in Later Medieval Literature" by Anna Elizabeth Francione 1981 (Box 4)
- "Gerald Manley Hopkins and the Imagination: The Struggle Toward Salvation" by Brent Hendricks 1981 (Box 5)
- "Death Notices and Other Stories" by Tom Jencks 1981 (Box 5)
- "The Beginning of Confusion: A Study of Certain Canonical Works of American Literature During the 1920's" by Jonathan D. Little 1981 (Box 5)
- "After such Knowledge, what forgiveness? A Study of the Poetry of T.S. Eliot and Robert Lowell" by George W. Penniman 1981 (Box 5)
- "A Union of Opposites: Yeat's Ireland during the Literary Revival" by Carol Ann Petravage 1981 (Box 5)
- "On a Higher Plain: Man and the Land in Contemporary Southwestern Fiction" by Kip Purcell 1981 (Box 5)
- "Time in Proust and James: A study in Technique as a Mode of Vision" by Richard Jahan Ramazani 1981 (Box 5)
- "Human Dichotomy in the Films of Fritz Lang" by Leslie Joanne Rodier 1981 (Box 5)
- "A Critical Reading of Virginia Wolf's Mrs. Dalloway, To The Lighthouse, and The Waves" by David Schlapbach 1981 (Box 5)
- "Flannery O' Connor: Christian Realist" by Caroline V. Taylor 1981 (Box 6)
- "The Role and Consciousness of Black Women in Hurston, Petry, and Walker" by Lisa Thompson 1981 (Box 6)
- "Vision and the Demands of Form: A Reading of Henry James's The Ambassadors" by Sara B. Blair 1982 (Box 6)
- "Incidents of Travel in Riversford" by Thomas Bolt 1982 (Box 6)
- "Wordsworth and Proust: The Redemptive Power of Memory" by Alexander F. Burnett 1982 (Box 6)
- "Poetry, Politics, and the Projector: The Semiology of Jean-Luc Godard's Weekend" by Achmad M. Chadran 1982 (Box 6)
- "Vision: Yeat's Plays" by Arthur Cronin 1982 (Box 6)
- "A Harlequin Thesis" by Pat Croskery 1982 (Box 6)
- "A Study in Comedy and the Elan Vital of John Earth" by Maryse Celine Dominguez 1982 (Box 6)
- "A Pilgrimage Through Four Centuries" by William R. Harrison 1982 (Box 7)
- "Chivalry in Sir Thomas Malory's Morte D'Arthur" by Heike Andren Kubasch 1982 (Box 7)
- "Vorticism: The Aesthetics of a Machine-Age Renaissance" by Wendy McGarvie 1982 (Box 7)
- "Chrysalis" by Thomas Martin Puckett 1982 (Box 7)
- "A Socio-Psychological Analysis of Four Lais of Marie de France" by Ruth Schwartz 1982 (Box 7)
- "Faith in a Pantheistic Reality" by Jessica Wylie Seaton 1982 (Box 7)
- "The Individual and Community in Toni Morrison's Novels: Integration Through Creativity" by Cynthia Kay Stewart 1982 (Box 7)
- " The Death of Artemio Cruz, Where the Air is Clear, and Aura: Time and Memory in the Works of Carlos Fuentes" by Jennifer Lynn Belk 1983 (Box 7)
- "A Grandchild of the Divine Mind: Chaucer's Franklin as a Generous Creator" by Glen Edward Brace 1983 (Box 7)
- "My Kingdom Stands on Brittle Glass: Christian Existentialist Approach to Richard III and Macbeth" by David Bernhard Brakke 1983 (Box 7)
- "Reading Matters: A Reading of Donald Barthleme's Snow White" by Margaret Case 1983 (Box 8)
- "The Ideal of Erotic Love in Sidney's Arcadia" by Michael Christopher Collins 1983 (Box 8)
- "A Pilgrimage Inward: The Augustinian Conflict Within the Canterbury Pilgrims" by Robert F. Donnelly Jr. 1983 (Box 8)
- "Generic Exploration: The Films of Altmann, Coppola, and Scorsese" by Michael W. Fleming 1983 (Box 8)
- "Lewis Carroll: Creator of Special Worlds for Adults and Children" by Katherine G. Fulhum 1983 (Box 8)
- "T.S. Eliot's 'Individual Talent': The surrender in his Poetry and his Criticism" by Amy Yvette Garrou 1983 (Box 8)
- "A celebration of Prosperity: The Social and Personal Implications of Affluence in John Updike's Rabbit is Rich by Valerie Ann Hastings 1983 (Box 8)
- "T.S. Eliot's Contemporary Drama: A Christian-Existentialist Perspective" by Robert Nels Hoglund 1983 (Box 8)
- "The Kafaesque Woman: Women Perceived through the Eyes of Kafka's Heroes" by Hilary White Holladay 1983 (Box 8)
- "Lautreamont and the Advent of Literary Surrealism: Objective Goals and Subjective Limitations in Les Chants du Maldoror" by Renee Hom 1983 (Box 8)
- "The Value of Brevity: A Study of Dubliners and A Haunted House and Other Short Stories" by Margaret R. Kostich 1983 (Box 9)
- "In Defense of Doris Lessing's Shikasta: A Fable for Our Times" by Giavanna Jo Munafo 1983 (Box 9)
- "A Butterfly's Wings Upon the Arches of a Cathedral: The Artistic Vision in Virginia Woolf's To The Lighthouse" by Walther Douglass Payne 1983 (Box 9)
- "The Outbreak of the Definite Mimetic Representation in the Later James" by Kenneth J. Pfaehler 1983 (Box 9)
- "The King Within: The Role of Faith in Tennyson's Idylls of the King" by Paige S. Price 1983 (Box 9)
- "Explanations of Evil: The Role of the Villain in Othello, The Duchess of Malfi and Paradise Lost" by Robert Francis Redmund, Jr. 1983 (Box 9)
- "The Curser of Ownership in William Faulker's Novels: Go Down, Moses, Light in August & Absalom, Absalom" by James L. Rogers Jr. 1983 (Box 9)
- "Diagnosis and Attempted Resolution of Social Problems: A Comparative Reading of Tennyson's Idylls of the King and Eliot's Waste Land" by David Bradley Sullivan 1983 (Box 9)
- "Finding A Voice in Literature: A Study of Doris Lessing, Adrienne Rich and Sylvia Plath" by Tracey O. Teets 1983 (Box 10)
- "Mrs. Ramsay, Lily and Woolf: How They Know What They Know" by Ann Vigo 1983 (Box 10)
- "Night Crew" by Peter Walpole 1983 (Box 10)
- "Truth and Conrad" by Donald J. Willey 1983 (Box 10)
- "Urban Renewal: Gwendolyn Brook's Attempt to Renovate Bronzeville" by Marvin Alton Artis 1984 (Box 10)
- "Social Commitment and Literature in Conflict: The Case of Andre Gide" by Joseph Roland Baker III 1984 (Box 10)
- "Alienation from the Good and True: The progression form a Christian to an Unconscious Model of the Self in the Works of Dostoyevdky and Hawthorne" by Russell B. Batson 1984 (Box 10)
- "The Amazingly Difficult and Vital Business of Human Relationship: A study of Four Novels by DH Lawrence" by Christopher Bayard 1984 (Box 10)
- "Stephen + Bloom= Joyce; Ulysses as Spiritual Autobiography" by Donald Boyle Jr. (Copy 1) 1984 (Box 10)
- "Stephen + Bloom= Joyce; Ulysses as Spiritual Autobiography" by Donald Boyle Jr. (Copy 2) 1984 (Box 11)
- "Federico Fellini and the Road to 8-1/2: From Democrat to Diarist" by Stephen Richard Daly 1984 (Box 11)
- "Lewis Carroll: Creator of Special Words For Adults and Children" by Katherine G. Fulghum 1984 (Box 11)
- "CLASC: Charlottesville's Central American Connection by Elizabeth Anne Gropman 1984 (Box 11)
- "The Daybook of Anna Maria Jackson Decamp Morris, 1850-1858" by Margaret Muth Hohmann 1984 (Box 11)
- "The Theoretical Implications of Dziga Vertov's The Man With a Movie Camera" by Andrew Stuart Marcus 1984 (Box 11)
- "Areas of Gray: Symbolism of Dark and Light in the Art of Joseph Conrad" by Suzanna Martens 1984 (Box 12)
- "From Darkness to Light and Back Again: The Victorian Novel of Religious Conversion" by Brian Martin Mulcahy 1984 (Box 12)
- "Satire in the Eighteenth Century: The Relative Influence of Horace and Juvenal in Henry Fielding's The Historical Registrar and Jonathan Wild" by Stacey P. Nakasian 1984 (Box 12)
- "Am I, Perhaps, A Woman?: Dialetics Give Birth in Ingmar Bergman's Sawdust and Tinsel, Persona and Fanny and Alexander" by Kimberly Anne Newman 1984 (Box 12)
- "The Old Order Changeth: Tradition and Transition in Thomas Hardy's Later Novels" by Emily Oliver 1984 (Box 12)
- "Alow and Aloft: A Study of Nautical Fiction in the Nineteenth Century" by Jeffrey J. Seiken 1984 (Box 12)
- "The Salvation of Mankind, The Salvation of Man: The Role of the Artist in Wordsworth and Joyce" by Christopher P. Spera 1984 (Box 12)
- (Box 12)
- "Courtly Love, Hermaphrodite, and Amoret in The Faerie Queene" by James Milton Starr 1984 (Box 12)
- "Heaven in A Wild Flower: Blake's Search for Happiness in This World" by Linda Lee Stringer 1984 (Box 12)
- "Mermaids in a Ship's Cabin: The Significance of Water in Nineteenth and Twentieth Century Literature by Women" by Craig L. Sumberg 1984 (Box 13)
- "The Inward Quest" by Tracy K. Warren 1984 (Box 13)
- "Simone De Beauvoir and The Second Sex: Manifesto or Mistreatment" by Luis Alvarez Jr. 1985 (Box 13)
- "Dressing to Reveal: The Use of Clothing in Charlotte Bronte's Works" by Stephanie Ann Baker 1985 (Box 13)
- "Reaching for What Lies Near: Women And Duty in George Eliot's Fiction" by Sharon Rose Bellovin 1985 (Box 13)
- "Rhetorical Gesture and Moral Perspective in Webster's Tragic Drama" by Steve Danzis 1985 (Box 13)
- "Active Words and Poetic Deeds: The Lives of Thomas Merton and Daniel Berrigan" by Donald Albert Daugherty Jr. 1985 (Box 13)
- "The King and the Crown: Approaches of Power in Shakespeare's Second Tetralogy" by Stephen Patrick Demm 1985 (Box 13)
- "Emily and Charlotte of the Psychologist's Couch: A Psychoanalytic Examination of Wuthering Heights and Jane Eyre" by Jeffrey Howard Dygert 1985 (Box 13)
- "Creating Something Else to be: Zora Neale Hurston and Anthropologist, Folkorist, and Novelist" by Lisa Moffitt Fisher 1985 (Box 13)
- "The Ambivalence of the Afro-American Identity" by Melody Forrester 1985 (Box 13)
- "The Romantic Concepts of Nineteenth Century Medievalists" by Bruce Glassco 1985 (Box 14)
- "Friendship and Independence; Ishmael's Quest in Moby Dick" by Brenda J. Goodwin 1985 (Box 14)
- "An Insider's View of the Insider's View: An Examination of Contemporary Appalachian Fiction" by Eleanor Farley Kern 1985 (Box 14)
- "Walt Whitman: A Journey into the Poetic Self" by Catheryn Lynne Mason 1985 (Box 14)
- "Recollection and Discovery: The Religious Literature of Flannery O' Conner and Walker Percy" by Cynthia Michele Maupin 1985 (Box 14)
- "A Mission of Opulence: The Puritan and Romantic Program of America Seen by Scott Fitzgerald" by Elizabeth Mazzola 1985 (Box 14)
- "Energy, Gaiety, Horseplay, Bickerings, Weariness: Thomas Hardy's Rule of Entropy" by William Penner 1985 (Box 14)
- "The Progression of Being: A Study of Martin Heidegger and T.S. Eliot" by Susan Marie Reiss 1985 (Box 14)
- "Man's Criminal Beginnings: A comparative Study of Taboo from the Miltonic and Freudian Perspectives" by Lin Marie Trucksess 1985 (Box 14)
- "Idiots and Lunatics: Men and Women in the Fiction of Rebecca West" by Margaret M. Willingham 1985 (Box 14)
- "Doubting Husbands, Doleful Wives: A Study of Sexual Politics in Shakespeare" by Jessie Therese Wooller 1985 (Box 15)
- "A Hard-Won Triumph: Water, Music, and the Growling Consciousness of the Self" by Cecilia Jane Wright 1985 (Box 15)
- "Walker Percy's Sovereign Reader: A Study in Narrative Form" by Jennifer Marie DiLalla 1986 (Box 15)
- "The Play is Memory: Theatre as the Union of Past and Present in the Drama of Tennessee Williams" by Lurana Joan Donnels 1986 (Box 15)
- "Chronicles In Stone: The Role of Architecture in Four Novels by Thomas Hardy" by John Bromiley Eagleson 1986 (Box 15)
- "The Contained Flower: An Analysis of Theodore Roethke's 'Lost Son' Sequence" by George Estreich 1986 (Box 15)
- "I Can Love Both Fair and Brown: The Woman in John Donne's Poetry" by Rebecca Garrou 1986 (Box 15)
- "Mazes of Wind-Music: Rereading the Postmodern Vision of William Blake" by Gregory J. Jones 1986 (Box 15)
- "F. Scott Fitzgerald and John Dos Passos: Views of the American 1920s" by Nina Michaela Kooij 1986 (Box 15)
- "Storms of the Heart and Mind: Three Journeys Into Self Awareness" by Nesita Kwan 1986 (Box 16)
- "Transience, Recurrence, and 'Momentary' Stays' Time In the Poetry of Robert Frost" by Laurie Frances Leach 1986 (Box 16)
- "Anna Livia Plurabelle and the Feminine Language of James Joyce's Finnegans Wake" by Shelly J. McQuone 1986 (Box 16)
- "Let Me Not Deceive Myself" by Rose Patricia Passalacqua 1986 (Box 16)
- "Thomas Mann: The Magician and the Making of Illusion" by Holly Beth Purinton 1986 (Box 16)
- "The Masquerade in Flames: Sylvia Plath's Masks of Stasis and Transformation" by Jeremy David Quittner 1986 (Box 16)
- "The philosophy of Ralph Waldo Emerson: Freedom and Pragmatism" by Michael Eugene Toner 1986 (Box 16)
- "Seamus Heaney and the Arguments: Splits, Complexities, and Embodiment" by Melanie Almeder 1987 (Box 16)
- "Community, Solitude, and Poetic Identity: An Approach to the relationship of Wordsworth and Coleridge" by Charles Thomas Blair 1987 (Box 16)
- "Women in the Fiction of Ellen Gilchrist: Moving Toward a Modern definition of the Southern Lady" by Sarah F. Bruce 1987 (Box 17)
- "Do Not Ask Me To Remain the Same: The Critical Ethos of Michel Foucault" by P.S. Burton 1987 (Box 17)
- "Unpathed Waters, Undreamed Shores: Images and Actions of the Sea in Shakespearean Romance" by Christopher Pearse Cahill 1987 (Box 17)
- (Box 17)
- "Loving The Enigma: Uses of Prosody in the Poetry of Sylvia Plath" by Hamilton Hill Cain 1987 (Box 17)
- "The Indecipherable Identity: Joseph Conrad's Failure in Heart of Darkness, Lord Jim and Nostromo" by Eric G. Iverson 1987 (Box 17)
- "Dead or Alive? The State of Southern Fiction" by Susan Randolph 1987 (Box 17)
- "A Pilgrim's Progress Through the Looking-Glass" by Julia Ann Rottman 1987 (Box 17)
- "Good night, Sweet Ladies, Good night: Gossip and Gospel In The Waste Land" by Karin L. Voth 1987 (Box 17)
- "In the Mother Without Knowing Her: Female Bonding in Three Novels of Henry James by Gayle F. Wald 1987 (Box 17)
- "Mrs. Gaskell's One Percent: The Role of Women in the Novels of Elizabeth Gaskell" by Melissa Lynne Welstead 1987 (Box 17)
- "The Fire of Stress: Gerald Manley Hopkin's and Francis Thompson's Poetics of the Incarnation" by Joseph Michael Bizup 1988 (Box 18)
- "The Metamorphosis of John Keats" by Richard Burch Commons 1988 (Box 18)
- "Lamia and the Argument of Beauty" by Rebecca Marie Cross 1988 (Box 18)
- "Impossible Dialectics: the novels of Virginia Woolf" by Margaret A. Debelius 1988 (Box 18)
- "Me Marlow, You Kurtz: Civilization, The Jungle, and the Pursuit of Happiness in Edgar Rice Burrough's Tarzan of the Apes and Joseph Conrad's Heart of Darkness" by Stephen Bitoni Dobranski 1988 (Box 18)
- "...because life is an incessant disruption of order...: Reading Milan Kundera" by Nona Kathryn Karnes 1988 (Box 18)
- "...And visions of Pear Trees Danced in their heads: Value Conflict and Magical Realism in Selected Works of Four Afro-American Writers" by Jane Harriet Lovitch 1988 (Box 18)
- "The shadows that both offend and Mend: A Literary and Theatrical Interpretation of A Midsummer Night's Dream" by Sarah Josephine Lyman 1988 (Box 18)
- "With other notes that to the Orphean lyre: Milton, Ovid and the self representation of the artist in Paradise Lost" by Sarah Elizabeth Powell 1988 (Box 18)
- "Finding a Place in a World Called Art: A Portrait of the Modern Bildungsroman" by Lisa Rado 1988 (Box 18)
- "Wallace Stevens: A Nighttime Self in a Daytime World" by Beth Ann Rothermel 1988 (Box 18)
- "This is a Marvelous Thing and an Adventurous: The Use of the Supernatural in Medieval Literature" by Ingrid A. Steffensen 1988 (Box 18)
- "The Continuing Genesis Tradition: A Study of Paradise Lost and its Relationship to Jewish Interpretation of Evil and the Fall" by W. Frank Taylor 1988 (Box 19)
- "Cosmic Talk and the Psychoanalytic Cure: Julia Kristeva" and the Influence of Jacques Lacan by Laurie A. Chreitzberg 1989 (Box 19)
- "The Advantage of Not Being Air; A Thematic Introduction to Lord Byron's Don Juan" by Ian Barnett Clarke 1989 (Box 19)
- "Who is my neighbor? The theme of Interconnection in Bleak House, Little Dorrit, Great Expectations, and Our Mutual Friend" by Mary Kathleen Lenard 1989 (Box 19)
- "Must a Sunny Imagination Hope? I am troubled." by Elizabeth Mullins 1989 (Box 19)
- "London: Dichotomy and Duality-In Howards End and Mrs. Dalloway" by Jennifer M. Olsen 1989 (Box 19)
- "Life and Verse: Issues of Freedom in the Writings of Marianne Moore" by Victoria Olwell 1989 (Box 19)
- "Living With Love; The Legacy of DH Lawrence" by Brad Phillips 1989 (Box 19)
- "Unmasking the Slave Narrative: Literacy, Liberty, and the Quest for Individual Identity" by Robert Cloud Seals Jr. 1989 (Box 19)
- "A Purplish Stain Upon the Bland Surface of the Sea: The Effects of Suppressed Female Anger in George Eliot's narratives" by Noelle C. Wainright 1989 (Box 20)
- "Nietzsche vs. Yeats: Self and Soul, Sun and Moon" by Ross J. Wehner 1989 (Box 20)
- "The Business of Evil" by James T. Blanch 1990 (Box 20)
- "Chaucer's Criseyde and Shakespeare's Troilus: Understanding...whether goddess or woman...She be... and What Cressid is-" by Anna C. Brickhouse 1990 (Box 20)
- "A Quest for Freedom: The Transcendent Ideals of Sylvia Plath and Adrienne Rich" by Jean S. Clark 1990 (Box 20)
- "A Dance of Opposites: A Feminist Examination of D.H. Lawrence Portrayal of Gender and Sexuality in Women in Love" by Christie Lynn Cox 1990 (Box 20)
- "The Interplay of Artistic Visions in Vladimir Nabokov's Lolita" by Aaron Crippen 1990 (Box 20)
- "The Possibility of Solace in the Dramatic Work of Samuel Beckett" by Stefani Elise Goldenberg 1990 (Box 20)
- "The Soul is But a Manner of Being: Interpenetrative Binary Structures in Vladimir Nabokov's The Real Life of Sebastian Knight and Pale Fire" by Carey Ellen Hagan 1990 (Box 20)
- "Distinguished Majors Program Thesis" by Julie Bond Hassel 1990 (Box 20)
- "No Way Out: Gender Roles and Society in The Return of the Native, The Mayor of Casterbridge, and Jude the Obscure" by Karen Elizabeth Hottle 1990 (Box 20)
- "James' Subtle Architecture: an Examination of the House Metaphor as a Vehicle for Thematic Expression in Daisy Miller" by Floyd Ronald Jenkins Jr. 1990 (Box 20)
- "Making Sense of the Fantastic in Sam Shepard: Knowing When to Leave the Theater' by Dennis George Jerz 1990 (Box 21)
- "Madness and Magic in Caribbean Women's Literature" by Dora Melez 1990 (Box 21)
- "Questions of Genre and Declarations of Agency if Harriet Wilson's Our Nig and Harriet Jacobs' Incidents in the Life of a Slave Girl" by Margaret Ross Proctor 1990 (Box 21)
- "From Rural California to Deep Space-And Back The Ecological Thought of Ursula K. Le Guin" by Robert Von Stein Redick 1990 (Box 21)
- "The Battle of Her Life: Personal desire and Social Duty in the World of George Eliot" by Robert John Sloane 1990 (Box 21)
- "The double sorwe of Troikus to tellen: Narrative Purpose in Chaucer's Troilus and Criseyde" by John F. Stinneford 1990 (Box 21)
- "Coping With Absurd: Artificial Extended Families in the Work of Kurt Vonnegut" by Patrick J. Thompson 1990 (Box 21)
- "Distinguished Majors Thesis" by Aleandra Valre White 1990 (Box 21)
- "Sapphic Broadcasting: Virginia Woolf's Lesbian Code-making in A Room of One's Own, Orlando, and Between the Acts" by Michael Albo 1991 (Box 21)
- "The Redefining Poet: Shelly's Views on Imagination in Mont Blanc, Julian and Maddalo and Prometheus Unbound" by Lee Behlamam 1991 (Box 21)
- "The Seeds of Disobedience: Keats's Relation to Swinburne" by Savannah Rose Blackwell 1991 (Box 21)
- "The Politics of Feminine Desire: Anthony and Cleopatra and the Duchess of Malfi" by Jennifer Lynn Brown 1991 (Box 22)
- "The Idea Imagination and Restraint in Conrad's Heart of Darkness, Lord Jim and Under Western Eyes" by John Frederick Dickerson 1991 (Box 22)
- "Robert Penn Warren and Myths of America" by Laura Winifred Guthrie 1991 (Box 22)
- "A Reason to Go Back Down to the Plain: Coherence, Society, and Forgiveness in William Syron's Sophie's Choice" by Pamela Susanne Hammons 1991 (Box 22)